Guide to the Alexander William Evans Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Alexander William Evans papers
1931-1959
MS 866
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
1.5
(4 boxes)
The papers contain correspondence covering Evans' tenure as curator and curator emeritus of the Eaton Herbarium and other botanical collections and primarily concern collecting and identifying species of lichens, mosses, liverworts and other plants.
Evans, Alexander W. (Alexander William), 1868-1959
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred from Kline Science Library, Yale University, in 1977.
Arrangement
Correspondence is arranged chronologically.
Scope and Contents
These papers consist of correspondence of Alexander William Evans, professor of botany at Yale University from 1901 to 1959 and chairman of the Department of Botany from 1920 to 1927. The correspondence, which is arranged chronologically, dates from Evans' tenure (1928-1959) as curator and curator emeritus of the Eaton Herbarium and other botanical collections, and concerns primarily the collection and identification of various species of lichens, mosses, liverworts, and other plants. Evans correspondents include botanists from America, Europe, India, Japan, and elsewhere.
Biographical / Historical
Ph.B., Yale, 1890, M.D., 1892, Ph.D., 1899, asst. prof. of botany, Yale, 1901-1906; prof. of botany, 1906-1959.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Botany; Plants -- Classification; Science; Botanists; Evans, Alexander W. (Alexander William), 1868-1959; Yale University -- Faculty
- Inventory, 1931-1959; 1.5' (4 boxes)
  - Correpondence
    - 1931-1944 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1945 January-February (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1945 March-May (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 1945 June-August (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 1945 September (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 1945 October (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 1945 November (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - 1945 December (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - 1946 January-February (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - 1946 March-April (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - 1946 May-July (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - 1946 August-October (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - 1946 November-December (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - 1947 January-February (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - 1947 March-April (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - 1947 May-June (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - 1947 July-September (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - 1947 October (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - 1947 November (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - 1947 December (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - 1948 January-February (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - 1948 March April (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - 1948 May (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - 1948 June-August (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - 1948 September-October (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - 1948 November (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - 1948 December (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - 1949 January (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - 1949 February (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - 1949 March-April (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - 1949 May-June (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - 1949 July-September (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - 1949 October-December (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - 1950 January (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - 1950 February (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - 1950 March (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - 1950 April (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - 1950 May (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - 1950 June (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - 1950 July-August (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - 1950 September (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - 1950 October (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - 1950 November (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - 1950 December (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - 1951 January (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - 1951 February (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - 1951 March-April (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - 1951 May-June (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - 1951 July-September (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - 1951 October (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - 1951 November (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - 1951 December (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - 1952 January (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - 1952 February-March (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - 1952 April-May (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - 1952 June-July (Box 3, Folder 56)
    - 1952 August (Box 3, Folder 57)
    - 1952 September (Box 3, Folder 58)
    - 1952 October (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - 1952 November-December (Box 3, Folder 60)
    - 1953 January-February (Box 3, Folder 61)
    - 1953 March-May (Box 3, Folder 62)
    - 1953 June-July (Box 3, Folder 63)
    - 1953 August-September (Box 3, Folder 64)
    - 1953 October-December (Box 3, Folder 65)
    - 1954 January-February (Box 3, Folder 66)
    - 1954 March (Box 3, Folder 67)
    - 1954 April-May (Box 3, Folder 68)
    - 1954 June-July (Box 3, Folder 69)
    - 1954 August-October (Box 3, Folder 70)
    - 1954 November (Box 3, Folder 71)
    - 1954 December (Box 3, Folder 72)
    - 1955 January (Box 3, Folder 73)
    - 1955 February (Box 3, Folder 74)
    - 1955 March (Box 3, Folder 75)
    - 1955 April (Box 3, Folder 76)
    - 1955 May-June (Box 3, Folder 77)
    - 1955 July-September (Box 3, Folder 78)
    - 1955 October-November (Box 3, Folder 79)
    - 1955 December (Box 3, Folder 80)
    - 1956 January-February (Box 4, Folder 81)
    - 1956 March-April (Box 4, Folder 82)
    - 1956 May (Box 4, Folder 83)
    - 1956 June-July (Box 4, Folder 84)
    - 1956 August-September (Box 4, Folder 85)
    - 1956 October (Box 4, Folder 86)
    - 1956 November-December (Box 4, Folder 87)
    - 1957 January (Box 4, Folder 88)
    - 1957 February-March (Box 4, Folder 89)
    - 1957 April-May (Box 4, Folder 90)
    - 1957 June August (Box 4, Folder 91)
    - 1957 September-October (Box 4, Folder 92)
    - 1957 November-December (Box 4, Folder 93)
    - 1958 January-April (Box 4, Folder 94)
    - 1958 May-December (Box 4, Folder 95)
    - 1959 January-June (Box 4, Folder 96)
    - 1959 July-Oct, undated (Box 4, Folder 97)